Robert H. Kokernot papers FA1407
Rockefeller Archive Center
Robert H. Kokernot papers
1946-2016
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
Kokernot, Robert H.
FA1407
4.65 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box, 2 letter-size document boxes, and 82 film canisters
82 Reels 16mm film
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916).
Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
The Robert H. Kokernot papers document Kokernot's daily work and travels as a staff member of the Rockefeller Foundation's arbovirus research program in South Africa from 1954-1960 and in Colombia from 1962-1963. The papers also provide a personal view into the social and domestic life of a white American family in apartheid South Africa in the 1950s.
Robert Kokernot's collection also includes films documenting both his research expeditions and his family's activities and travel.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Peggy Kokernot Kaplan donated the Robert H. Kokernot papers to the Rockefeller Archive Center as an unrestricted gift on November 30, 2017.
Related Materials
Additional materials relating to Robert H. Kokernot are found in the Rockefeller Foundation records, including Officers' Diaries (FA392) (a partial copy of his diaries for 1954-1957); FA425 and FA400, General Correspondence for 1954-1956 and 1958-1963; and a Biographical File in FA1280, Secretary's Office, RG 15, series 4. Other materials include a correspondence file in the Kenneth C. Smithburn papers (FA040), and a file in the John C. Bugher papers (FA027).
Kokernot's correspondence with Edith May Babcock, 1943-1946, is found in the Texas A and M University archives.
Arboviruses; South Africa; Mozambique; Botswana; Colombia; Angola; Arthropod vectors
- Personal and Professional Papers, 1949-2016; 1951-1975; 1; 1.41 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box, 2 letter-size document boxes; 1 flat file folder, and 6 DVDs.
  Scope and Contents
  Robert H. Kokernot was a staff member of the Johannesburg arbovirus laboratory from 1954 to 1960. His professional papers consist of the official diaries he kept of his laboratory work and his field expeditions into Mozambique, the Caprivi Strip and Bechuanaland Protectorate, and Angola, and of his exploratory travel in Colombia in 1962-1963. Diary notes from his home leaves in 1956 and 1958 also include details of visits with Rockefeller Foundation officers and colleagues. The file includes articles reporting on results of Kokernot's research in Africa and his subsequent work in the U.S. While there is little professional correspondence in the file, Kokernot's personal letters home sometimes include details on his travel and research.
  The Family Correspondence files consist primarily of letters from Kokernot and his wife Edith Babcock Kokernot to Robert's mother and stepfather, Lucy (Moss Kokernot) and Ray White, in Chico, CA. Living abroad with three young children, Edith and Robert wrote letters detailing the children's growth, schooling, friends, and holidays; their own activities and social life; the family's travels in South Africa; and their travels to and from home.
  In retirement, Kokernot wrote an autobiographical account of his life up to the 1970s, and he compiled a volume about his travel and research in Africa and Colombia. These accounts reproduce various sections of his diaries and his film guides.
  - Biographical Materials and Obituary, 2004, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Family Correspondence (6 folders), 1949, 1952-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2-7)
    File consists primarily of letters from Robert Kokernot and Edith Babcock Kokernot to Robert's parents, Lucy and Ray White, in Chico, CA. Subjects concern daily life in South Africa, the children's growth and activities, health, social life, and travel, as well as the progress of Robert's research and field work.
  - Kenneth Smithburn Correspondence, 1950-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Diary Notes, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Covers period January 29, 1954 - December 1956. Entries for 1956 tend to be summary reports. Diary entries document Kokernot's laboratory research, field work, and travel in South Africa as a staff member of the Rockefeller Foundation's virus laboratory. The volume also includes a summary of Kokernot's activities while absent from Johannesburg, March 22 - July 23, 1956.
    This diary volume closely parallels the copy of his diary found in the Rockefeller Foundation records, Officers' Diaries. But there are some differences between them, particularly for entries toward the end of 1955 and 1956.
  - Diary Notes, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Diary covers January 1, 1957 - August 31, 1959. Includes field trips to Portuguese East Africa (Mozambique), July 11 - August 23, 1957; Lumbo, Mozambique, March 11 - April 8, 1959; and Caprivi Strip and Bechuanaland Protectorate, May 25 - July 2, 1959. Note that this volume includes entries for August-December 1957 that are not found in the Rockefeller Foundation records, Officers' Diaries volume for that year.
  - Diary Notes, 1959 September - 1960 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
    File consists of loose diary pages that had been inserted at the back of the 1957-1959 volume.
  - Diary Notes on Special Expeditions, 1957, 1959-1960, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Trips to Portuguese East Africa (Mozambique), 1957 July 11 - August 23; Lumbo, Mozambique, 1959 March 11 - April 8; Caprivi Strip and Bechuanaland Protectorate, 1959 May 25 - July 2: Portuguese West Africa (Angola), 1960 May 27 - June 23; Colombia, Llanos and Amazonas, 1962 August 26 - September 3.
  - Diary Notes - Home Leaves from South Africa, 1956, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Home leaves March 22 - July 23, 1956, and June 18 - November 8, 1958. Copies of pages from Kokernot's diary volumes.
  - Publications and Reprints, 1957-1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Passports, 1953-2000 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    File also includes a leather passport case embossed with the Rockefeller Foundation's logo and Kokernot's Rockefeller Foundation - issued travel ID.
  - Autobiography, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Robert H. Kokernot, A Factual Account in the Life of a Fortunate Man: The First Six Decades, San Antonio, TX, 2002. Volumes 1 and 2, in one bound volume. Pp. i-iii, 1-240; and i-iii, 1-182.
  - Travels in David Livingstone's Southern Africa and the Llanos and Amazonas of Columbia, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Volume compiled and authored by David Kokernot. Contents consist of indexes and descriptive guides to Kokernot's films of Africa and Colombia; copies of his diaries of field trips to Mozambique, Caprivi Strip and Bechuanaland Protectorate, Angola, and Colombia, 1957-1962; reprints of his survey reports; and some introductory notes and illustrations. The diaries and film guides also exist elsewhere in the collection; but we do not have other copies for some of the survey reports.
  - Guide to Films of Africa and Colombia, 1954-1963, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Index and description of Kokernot's 41 reels of film of Africa and Colombia. File also includes a second copy of the guide that matches a set of 6 VHS tapes to their corresponding film reels.
  - The Kokernot Children's Early Years Living in the USA and Abroad (Guide to Videos), 1950-1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Jan, Peggy, Walter, and Diana Kokernot - Their Early Years Living in the USA and Abroad - A Pictorial Account. Guide to the contents of 5 VHS cassettes (and presumably 6 DVDs of the same title). The sixth DVD includes Peggy Kokernot's interview of her paternal grandmother, Lucy Moss Kokernot White.
  - Jan, Peggy, Walter, and Diana Kokernot - The Early Years Living in the USA and Abroad (Disk 1), 1950-1967; DVD (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jan, Peggy, Walter, and Diana Kokernot - The Early Years Living in the USA and Abroad (Disc 2), 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jan, Peggy, Walter, and Diana Kokernot - The Early Years Living in the USA and Abroad (Disc 3), 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jan, Peggy, Walter, and Diana Kokernot - The Early Years Living in the USA and Abroad (Disc 4), 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jan, Peggy, Walter, and Diana Kokernot - The Early Years Living in the USA and Abroad (Disc 5), 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jan, Peggy, Walter, and Diana Kokernot - The Early Years Living in the USA and Abroad, and Interview with Granny (Disc 6), 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    This sixth DVD also includes Peggy Kokernot's interview of her paternal grandmother, Lucy Moss Kokernot White.
  - Family Photographs (Copies), 1950s, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Photocopied snapshots and images of Edith Kokernot and children, mid-1950s, and of Robert H. Kokernot in 1971. Includes photo of Kokernot daughters posing with Zulu wedding party, mid-1950s.
  - Worth, Mosquito Safari, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Mosquito Safari: A Naturalist in Southern Africa, by C. Brooke Worth (New York, 1971). Worth worked with Kokernot and provides accounts of some of their travels and field work.
  - Oversized Photographs (Folder 22)
    Two unidentified landscape scenes. Black-and-white prints, approximately 10.5" x 16" and 10" x 14.5." The first image may be of the Rio Raposa field station. The latter image, signed by Terence Spencer, is glued to a 16" x 20" paper backing. Both images have been removed from frames.
- Robert H. Kokernot Films, 1946-1975; 2; 3.23 Cubic Feet 82 film reels; 82 Reels 82 film reels
  Arrangement
  Films remain in Robert H. Kokernot's original order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916).
  Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  Films documenting Robert H. Kokernot's scientific work in Africa and Colombia for the Rockefeller Foundation. The Home Movies series documents his children's activities, family life, and travel in South Africa, Columbia, and the U.S.
  Moving Images
  - Africa and Colombia Films, 1954-1975; 1
    - Kokernot Film 1, 1957 July 11 - August 23; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2465)
      Open for research. Digital access copy available.
      Scenes in Mozambique
    - Kokernot Film 2, 1957 August 6-9; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2466)
      Mueda and Mocimboa do Rovuma
    - Kokernot Film 3, 1957 August 4; 1959 March 22; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2467)
      Island of Mozambique, Cabaceria
    - Kokernot Film 4, 1959 March-April; 1960 March; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2468)
      Lumbo
    - Kokernot Film 5, 1959 March 13; 1957 August 12; Silent, Color, 29 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2469)
      Initiating Field Work at Lumbo, Trip to the Island of Ibo
    - Kokernot Film 6, circa 1950s-1960s; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2470)
      Tongaland
    - Kokernot Film 7, circa 1950s-1960s; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2471)
      Painting Face (Mozambique), Fixing Hair and Preparation of Sugar Cane Drink, Collecting Bulbs and Kraal Scenes
    - Kokernot Film 8, 1960 May 27 - June 23; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2472)
      Angola - Sa da Banderia, Buco Zau
    - Kokernot Film 9, 1960 May 27 - June 23; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2473)
      Angola - Nova Lisboa
    - Kokernot Film 10, 1959 May 28 - June 10; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2474)
      Eastern Caprivi Strip and Mababe Depression
    - Kokernot Film 11, 1959 May - June; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2475)
      Okavango Swamp and Caprivi Strip
    - Kokernot Film 12, 1959 June; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2476)
      Sleeping Sickness in the Caprivi Strip and at Maun, Bechuanaland
    - Kokernot Film 13, 1959 June; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2477)
      Hottentots
    - Kokernot Film 14, 1959 June 28; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2478)
      Bushmen - Lone Tree, Obtaining Blood Specimens and General Scenes
    - Kokernot Film 15, 1959 June 28; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2479)
      Bushmen - Lone Tree: Skinning Springbok and General Views of Shelter for Sleeping and of the People
    - Kokernot Film 16, 1955 June 11-19; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2480)
      En Route to Victoria Falls
    - Kokernot Film 17, 1955 June 11-19; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2481)
      At Victoria Falls
    - Kokernot Film 19, 1960 May; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2482)
      Kruger National Park - Nwanedzi Camp and Olifants
    - Kokernot Film 20, circa 1960; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2483)
      Kruger National Park - Elephants Watering in River, Camp at Shingwidzi
    - Kokernot Film 21, circa 1960; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2484)
      Kruger National Park - Lunch on Hill Near Shigomane Look-Out Tower, Camp at Punda Milia and a Variety of Animals
    - Kokernot Film 22, circa 1960; Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2485)
      Black Herons Feeding at Simbu Pan Kruger National Park - Elephant at Parfuri, Lion (Changing of the Guard), Baobab Trees
    - Kokernot Film 23, 1957 July 25-26; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2486)
      Hluhluwe and Gorongosa Game Reserves
    - Kokernot Film 24, 1957 July 17-18; Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2487)
      Chopi Dancers at Zandamela, Mozambique
    - Kokernot Film 25, 1957 July 21; Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2488)
      Ruins Near Vilanculos, Mozambique - Khami Ruins Near Bulawayo - Zimbabwe Near Fort Victoria
    - Kokernot Film 26, circa 1955; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2489)
      Field Work - Mosquitoes, Monkeys, and Small Mammals
    - Kokernot Film 27, circa 1955; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2490)
      Field Work - Birds, People, Cattle, and Taking Specimens to Inhambane
    - Kokernot Film 28, circa 1950s-1960s; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2491)
      Laboratory Work - Serologic Tests (HAI, CF), Processing Mosquitoes, (NT), Response in Mice to Inoculation with Arboviruses, Mosquito Feeding
    - Kokernot Film 29, 1974 December 20-29; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2492)
      Lisbon, Tzaneen, Kruger National Park
    - Kokernot Film 30, 1974 December 28 - 1975 January 6; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2493)
      Kruger National Park, Near Pietermaritzburg, Hluhluwe Game Reserve, Ndum
    - Kokernot Film 31, 1975 January 5-24; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2494)
      Durban, Umhlanga Rocks, Oudtshoorn, Cape Town and Camps Bay, Victoria Falls, Egypt
    - Kokernot Film 32, 1962-1963; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2495)
      Rio Raposo Field Station
    - Kokernot Film 33, 1962-1963; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2496)
      Purace, Indian Market at Silvia, Jurado, Magdalena River
    - Kokernot Film 34A, 1962; Silent, Color, 10 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2497)
      Cartagena, Rio Raposa Field Station
    - Kokernot Film 34B, 1962; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2498)
    - Kokernot Film 35, 1962; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2499)
      Cali and Environs - Garden, Guy Hayes New House, Picnic, Country Home, Bullfight
    - Kokernot Film 36, 1962-1963; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2500)
      Cali and Environs - Garden, Christmas, Birthdays, Picnic
    - Kokernot Film 37, 1963 April; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2501)
      Pasto and Laguna de La Cocha
    - Kokernot Film 38, 1963 June 18-19; 1963 April; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2502)
      Rio Raposa and Popayan
    - Kokernot Film 39, 1962 August 28-September 2; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2503)
      Llanos and Amazonas
    - Kokernot Film 40, 1962 November -December; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2504)
      Guajira Peninsula - Man on Horse, Corn Gruel, Law Enforcement Man, Young Goat, Grinding Corn, Mosqito Collecting, Boys Face and Body Painting, Stew Cooking, House Building at Manaure, and Dance
    - Kokernot Film 41, 1962 November -December; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2505)
      Guajira Peninsula - Thorn Bush Vegetation, Flamingos, Donkey, Washing Clothes, Dancing, Blanket Weaving, and Milking
  - Kokernot Family Home Movies, 1946, 1950-1971; 2
    - Edith and Bob Kokernot Wedding, 1946; Silent, Color, 4 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2506)
      Wedding footage
    - Kokernot Family 1, 1950 January; Silent, Color, 14 minutes (Reel AV 2507)
      Five Days Old
      Other Finding Aids
      16mm film
    - Kokernot Family 2, 1951 December; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2508)
      Christmas in Baltimore
    - Kokernot Family 3, circa 1951-1952; Silent, Color, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2509)
      Jan's Second Birthday, Fairyland, Peggy in hospital, Christmas 1952, Paradise, California
    - Kokernot Family 4, 1953; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2510)
      Washing dogs in California, Leaving San Francisco, El Paso and Ranch, Sonora, Jan's 3rd birthday - New York City, Peggy and Jan in bathtub and asleep
    - Kokernot Family 5, 1953; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2511)
      Peggy's 1st Birthday, Thanksgiving in Baltimore, Maryland, Christmas - New York City
    - Kokernot Family 6, 1954; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2512)
      At sea, Pompeii, Damascus, Camel ride and pyramid, Kids and grace and Jack
    - Kokernot Family 7, 1954; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2513)
      Game Reserve
    - Kokernot Family 8, 1954-1955; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2514)
      Kids, Sliding, playing in sprinkler and mud, Jan's 4th and Peggy's 2nd Christmas, Swimming, Jan's 5th birthday
    - Kokernot Family 9, circa 1955; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2515)
      African ceremorial performance
    - Kokernot Family 10, circa 1955; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2516)
      Spelling Out South Africa, Pretoria tea party, Drakensburg, Grace and Edith K. pony ride, Durban, Marion Beach
    - Kokernot Family 11, 1955-1956; Silent, Color, 15 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2517)
      Peggy's 3rd Birthday, Christmas, Jan - school, Jan's 6th Birthday, Peggy's 4th Birthday
    - Kokernot Family 12A, 1956-1957; Silent, Color, 4 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2518)
      Christmas 1956, Jan's Birthday, Christmas 1957, Krueger
    - Kokernot Family 12B, circa 1956-1957; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2519)
      Peggy's Birthday, Christmas 1957, Kruger
    - Kokernot Family 13, circa 1956-1957; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2520)
      Trip Home: Capetown, Rio, Mexico
    - Kokernot Family 14, 1956; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2521)
      Returning To South Africa via North Pole, Denmark, and Rome, Chico, California
    - Kokernot Family 15, 1957; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2522)
      Walter
    - Kokernot Family 16, 1958; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2523)
      Returning To South Africa, Rome, Athens, Delphi
    - Kokernot Family 17, 1958; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2524)
      Durban - Grace and Edith, Drakensburg, Walter and family, January - his first steps, Walter's 1st Birthday, WHK 2nd Birthday, Mr. and Mrs. Babcock, George and Ethel Dumbauld
    - Kokernot Family 18, 1958; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2525)
      Jan's 8th Birthday, California
    - Kokernot Family 19, 1958; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2526)
      Clay Espy, Lisbon, Rome en route to South Africa
    - Kokernot Family 21, 1958; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2528)
      Brussells, London, New York, California, Zephyr
    - Kokernot Family 22, circa 1959 August-1960; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2529)
      Tropic of Capricorn, Peggy and Jan's Birthday, Christmas 1959, CB Worth, WHK 3rd Birthday
    - Kokernot Family 23, 1960 August; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2530)
      Zanzibar
    - Kokernot Family 24A, 1960 August; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2531)
      Venice en route to Vienna
    - Kokernot Family 24B, 1960 August; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2532)
      Paris
    - Kokernot Family 25, 1960-1961; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2533)
      Arrival in Baltimore 1960, Christmas - Granny and Popo, Diana born February 4, 1961
    - Kokernot Family 26, 1961; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2534)
      Walter's 4th Birthday, Bryn Maur, Bazzar, Drill
    - Kokernot Family 27, 1961 June-July; Silent, Color, 6 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2535)
      Lucille K., Gonzales cemetery, Aunt Theresa, Fred Junior, etc.
    - Kokernot Family 28, 1961; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2536)
      Grand Canyon, Zion, Granny and Popo, Panama Canal
    - Kokernot Family 29, 1961 June-July; Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2537)
      Lucille,Gertrude and Ed, Gonzales, Sonora, Diana's Christening, OGB, Mesa
    - Kokernot Family 30, 1961-1962; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2538)
      Diana (Fall 1961), Christmas 1962, Walter's 5th Birthday
    - Kokernot Family 31, 1963 July-August; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2539)
      Panama Canal
    - Kokernot Family 32, 1966; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2540)
      Ice skating, Cave in rock, Diana's 5th Birthday, Granny and Popo, Aunt Ethel visits
    - Kokernot Family 33, 1966; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2541)
      Experiment Station - Sonora, Texas, The Window - Big Bird, Santa Elena Canyon, En route to Presidio, Ranch - WHK, Native American Dance
    - Kokernot Family 34, 1967; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2542)
      Ice skating, Peggy - Track, Covered bridge, Maple syrup, Cheerleading - Peggy, County Fair Queen, Christmas - Jan K, Christmas 1967
    - Kokernot Family 35, 1967; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2543)
      Dianagoing to school, Jan's departure for Saltillo, RHK's departure for Paradiso, Church, Lassen, La Jolla, California
    - Kokernot Family 36, 1968-1969; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2544)
      1968: Dove "Joe" and Peggy, Mimi's puppies, Digging pool, WHK - Scout, Kokernot cemetary, Brackenridge Park, Baylor, Climbing on roof, Patti Lynn/ 1969: WHK at Memorial Junior High School, Football, Diana, Aunt Ann Moss, Aggies versus Rice
    - Kokernot Family 37, 1969 March; Silent, Color, 6 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2545)
      South of Big Bend
    - Kokernot Family 38, 1971 March; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2546)
      Baja, California, WHK track meet, Santa Elena raft trip
    - Kokernot Family 39, circa 1971; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2547)
      To California, Orville Lake, California, Water skiing, Hike up creek, Yellowstone National Park